Can I hold him?
Will you put him on me?
I want to put it on me.
- Can you put it on me?
- Just wait, guys.
Gentle.
Be very careful.
Close your eyeballs, close your eyeballs.
My God, I think it likes you...a lot.
Oh, my gosh, it's gonna climb on your eye!
You okay? You okay?
You're good?
Get it off her.
Don't scare him. Don't scare him.
Did that butterfly just come?
Shh. Go on, buddy.
You got him!
Oh, no!
So your whole hotel room
is a clear plastic bubble.
It's heated, it's everything...
Damn.
Help.
You look as beautiful
as the day I met you.
Even more, even more beautiful.
Don't forget to tie your shoelace.
Oh, I have your truck, Isaiah.
- Thank you.
- Okay.
Good night. Have a good night.
I'm going to the park.
My dad is very late.
- Came we come?
- No, your parents are here.
Daycare is closed. See you, guys.
Goodnight.
You are about to jump.
I haven't given them insurance.
Well we signed off all
of our rights already.
All you have to do to not
break your legs is lift them up.
Oh, my God.
You are soaking wet.
Oliver.
Like one minute now.
Put your goggles down.
Here we go!
There's that fear!
Okay. Fuck.
You're just swimming in your clothes?
- I can give him...
- What is that?
It's my shirt. It's pretty dry still.
Come here. Up.
Alright, get your stuff. Thank you.
I want you all to imagine this plane.
This tiny, tiny plane.
I want everyone to think about
a slight rumbling of the ground.
You're just...
Come on back to us.
Oh, there, you're back.
And...
You feel the lift off the ground.
And you feel the plane climbing,
and climbing
and climbing into the sky.
Sarah.
Whoosh, the door to the plane is open
and you're just hearing
all this rushing air.
You just hear, "Shh."
And then they pull the parachute
and it goes,
Ya! Ya! Ya!
Oh, my God.
We have a better for than you, boys.
- We don't care.
- Yes, you do.
What's the password?
What's happening under here?
We're just taking a mermaid nap.
A mermaid nap.
And mermaid bubbles.
You know what? You have to be up, okay?
You have to be eyes on the room.
Can you please get out of there?
Anne. Anne?
We gotta be role models
for these guys, okay?
- I'm playing with them.
- No, I know, I get that.
I just want you to know that I need
you on the floor, eyes on, okay?
You have to be able to do the job
at the same time. Okay?
So don't be weird.
- Don't be weird?
- There's just some drawings on the walls.
Drawings.
The guy in apartment 3 did all of this.
And the landlord got really pissed off
and the guy was like,
"I don't know,
I think I made it look better,"
and the landlord was just like,
"You just drew a bunch
of dicks on the walls.
How did you make it look better?"
But like,
then he didn't do anything about it so...
So what do you think?
I think it's nice.
The floors are fine.
Counter's good. Yeah.
Stove's good.
You're warm?
- Okay.
- Yeah.
And the landlord said
that he can put in an air condition unit.
Oh, good.
Yeah, that'll be great.
You feeling okay?
Yeah, I feel great. Yeah.
How's work and stuff?
Yeah, no, it's good.
It's like a little bit tiring but...
I think I'll get used to it,
used to doing the four shifts a week.
I just want to get the house really nice
so that I can have people over.
- Have you had people over?
- No.
Except for me.
Right.
I feel honoured.
Mums don't count.
Yeah, I know.
No, it looks good. Really good.
I am drawing a fairy with curly hair.
- Can I keep the picture?
- Yeah.
Who wants to give her another eyeball?
- I want to.
- No, remember when she said...
Parmis and I do some too.
It's fine.
Do you want to turn it into a boat?
No.
Look, you just turn it into a boat, look.
- Can I make some wild curls?
- Yeah, of course you can.
She can have curls for days.
Lunchtime!
- Who has washed their hands?
- I did!
Do you guys want to come
with me to wash your hands?
Have you washed your hands yet?
Hey Sophia,
why don't you come sit at this table?
There's still spots over here.
So as you know,
I came around this last week
and got everybody to sign
the new support plans
and at the moment
we have a couple of children
that are especially challenging.
I do want to stress that I've had a couple
of the parents come forward to me
and they're concerned that the staff
aren't being that supportive.
And what our role is,
from the city point of view,
is that we have to try everything.
That means that if we need extra support
we try and get extra staff in
or we try and do extra training.
I know it's hard,
but we've got to work together,
otherwise we could
have a human rights issue.
That would be awful
for the centre and the families.
Does anybody have any questions?
You know, I'm feeling really drained
because for instance last week
I was doing snack with seven kids
and I get punched
in the centre of by back.
My natural reaction would be like,
"What the hell is going on?"
but I have to be like,
"Oh, please don't do that."
I really don't feel like it's fair
that the city is putting this on us
to be able to deal with it
and I feel like they have a mandate
and this is what it is
and we really don't have a voice.
I know it's hard Asina
but we need to think of,
instead of the child misbehaving
they're stressed.
They're not handling
so that's our role.
I mean I don't care if a
kid is climbing all over me
or pulling my hair or something.
But what I have a problem with
is when there are different teachers
that are really judgmental
of the way you're dealing with a kid.
Yeah but some of us
have a lot more experience
and can see what's happening is not right.
Some of the teacher aren't
trying to gently guide others
- they're like...
- Yeah, we actually are.
Well, you know what, I think sometimes
people don't realize the entire situation
and they're kind of like,
"Ew, why is she doing that."
But we need to support each other.
And if come together as a team
and work together as a team
then I think that would help.
Okay. So maybe we can look at some courses
and maybe we can get some extra help
but you have to keep
talking to the three of us
so we know what's going on
and we can support you.
Yeah, and work together.
We all need to work together.
Sarah.
Sarah!
One, two, three...!
Sarah! Hi.
- How did you get up there?
- I flew.
- Do you want to come up here?
- Come up?
Welcome to my palace.
It's so nice.
That's amazing.
I like the wind.
Ever since we went skydiving
I just want to be really high up.
I want to work up until
being able to go by myself.
Yeah?
I didn't feel scared at all.
Really?
I was... yeah, I wasn't scared.
Just kidding. I was really scared.
Will you lift me?
Ready?
- Does it feel the same?
- No!
Ready?
Anne?
- I'm Pat.
- Hi.
- Nice to meet you. How are you?
- Nice to meet you too.
- I'm good. How are you?
- I'm doing well, thank you.
You look really different
than your picture.
I'm sorry?
You look really different
than your picture.
I do? Hope I didn't disappoint you.
No, that's not... You just look
like an entirely different person.
Is that a good thing or a bad thing?
I don't know.
Not good or bad.
Just... Just, dis concerting.
Well you look the same so...
When I saw your photo I went to the right
and you went to the right
when you saw mine and here we are.
Yeah.
I'm going to have a beer.
Alright. I'm having a Miller Light.
- Miller Light?
- Yeah.
- I'll have the same thing.
- Okay.
- Cheers.
- Yep, cheers.
Your shirt is very well ironed.
Thank you.
I do my own ironing.
Well, I live alone so,
you know, I have no choice.
Right. I mean,
you could go tot he dry-cleaners.
Oh I could.
Are you from the area?
Sort of yeah.
- Yeah, I mean, West End.
- Yeah.
And you're into... you work with kids?
I work at a daycare, yeah.
I'm not going to tell you which one,
because I don't know you yet.
Oh I mean, I understand sure.
I mean,
yeah we're basically two strangers.
This is the first time we met, right?
I know, I understand.
I work for insurances.
Feel free to go on
Mississaugalnsurances.com.
I'm there. You'll see my photo.
You'll see what I do.
We do everything.
Auto, boat... life insurance.
It's a good company.
Do you like to travel?
Not really.
I don't have the time.
There you go.
Perfect.
Okay, head up, just like that.
Go. Awesome.
Arms nice and even, right here.
Put pressure on my hands, just like that.
Head up. Perfect, okay, and relax.
Couple steps. And then at about 500 feet
we're gonna stop.
We're gonna pull down again
and we're gonna turn crosswind.
There you go.
And then hands all the way up. Perfect.
Now we're gonna fly crosswind
to the hangar so keep going,
couple more steps.
There you go. Arch. There we go.
Alright. Nice and hard.
There you go. Reach back.
And pull.
Fantastic.
Good job.
What did I want to find?
My hands were empty.
Perhaps it's upstairs then.
And in the garden, he whispered.
"Quietly." They said.
But it wasn't that you woke us, oh, no.
They're looking for it.
They're drawing the curtain one might say.
And so read on a page or two.
Now they found it.
One would be certain,
stopping the pencil on the margin
and then, tired of reading,
one might rise and see for oneself
the house all empty,
the door standing open,
only the wood pigeons
bubbling with content
and the hum of the threshing machine
sounding from the farm.
Anne, is that hot liquid?
You know we can't have it in here right?
Yeah, no, you're right. Sorry.
Anne, the thing is like,
if an inspector came in or something
it's on both of us right?
- It's both of our faults.
- Okay. Okay.
- Can you take care of it, please?
- Yep.
Seriously.
Why would you do that to me?
It's an empty cup.
I was just showing
you that I dumped it out.
It's all gone.
Thank you for dumping out the coffee
but, seriously,
don't throw things at me, ever.
I wouldn't do that to you
and I wouldn't do that to anyone else.
I mean, you're welcome to.
No that's okay.
It's extremely unprofessional.
It's empty. I dumped it down the sink.
Yeah, but you know what?
I got water on me.
I just want you to look nice.
I want you to feel good.
I want you to have a nice time.
I just want you to relax a little bit.
I'm not here to play.
I'm here to do my job.
Lookit.
Anne.
What can I do for you?
Because I think you're in trouble here.
I didn't touch you.
I put the drink in the cup holder.
- I put the drink in the cup holder.
- What is wrong with you?
I want to help you
but I can't if you're not gonna...
Do you need to go talk to somebody?
You're so, you're so dumb.
You're so dumb.
You think I want to work with you?
Hey.
Hey there, who'd you find huh?
Hello.
Good morning.
You okay?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Do you want to come
stay for a couple days?
No, that's okay. No.
I just stayed for the night.
Okay. Okay, but...
anytime, anything is overwhelming
or, I'm not saying it is but, you know,
it can get that way.
- No I get it.
- Cold feet.
Anytime at all, any length of time.
Okay but I'm just saying this
time I was just dropping in.
But if I need to stay
longer I will let you know.
I know that I can stay
and I appreciate it.
Okay.
And Ryan, do you take Sarah
to be your lawfully wedded wife,
to have and to hold
to honour and to cherish
as long as you both shall love?
I do.
Ryan, you may give her her ring.
It's my great honour
to pronounce you man and wife.
She looked so beautiful.
She did, I know.
Are you enjoying your bubbly yet?
Yeah, I'm gonna have to go back for more.
I can see that.
Can you tell me,
what is it like to be young and beautiful?
Oh I don't know.
No, you're living it. You must know.
It feels powerful.
Ooh. Very good answer. Very good.
And you know,
that's the best answer I've ever gotten.
She's gonna run the other way now.
You've scared her.
- You've scared her.
- Come here.
They're gonna have a
wonderful prosperous life.
They looked so matching.
Hi, my name is Anne and I work
at the Children's Circle with Sarah.
Um, when I first started
working at the daycare
she made me feel really welcomed
and even when I made
lots of mistakes with the kids,
like when I left a kid in his snowsuit
for a few hours inside and he fainted
yeah,
she didn't make me feel like an idiot.
So that was - and she
made the kid wake up.
She gave him some water,
which was nice.
Sarah, you're, yeah,
you just make everyone that's around you
feel really good about themselves.
And that they could do anything stupid
and that you'd probably forgive them.
If I...
If I didn't have you
when I was at the daycare
maybe... maybe I would
have gotten really in my head
and really scared that something
might happen to the kids.
And I might have thought
I was bad or something
and that I couldn't be around the kids.
But...
you made me feel that I was good
and that I could do my job
and that I could do a good job.
And, yeah, Ryan's really lucky.
And if you do anything
to hurt her I'll kill you.
No, I think you think you
guys'll be really happy.
And I don't know Ryan,
maybe he contributes too, I don't know.
Um... okay, I love you.
I love you too.
I liked your speech.
- Really?
- Yes, I loved it.
In fact, I thought it was
the most sincere thing that...
I thought it was better than the vows.
I liked the snowshoe - the snowsuit bit.
I liked the "you're
gonna kill the husband" bit,
- even though he's my best friend.
- That's a classic.
Always kills.
I stole that from other weddings.
Yeah, well, it always looks good
when the maid of honour
threatens to kill the new husband.
It's very animal kingdom.
Okay, I'm gonna go back
to the other side of the room and sit.
I just thought I'd come over and see
what this side of the room was like.
You're Matt, right?
I know you're Anne.
Okay, so how do you know the bride?
Didn't you hear my speech?
Okay, so that's where
you met her for real?
Okay, so wait a minute,
you've known Sarah three years
and you're already the maid of honour?
Did you have to kill everybody else?
- You guys are dancing?
- Yes.
I was telling her it was the best
bridesmaid speech I'd ever heard.
He said that everyone hated
my speech except for him.
- No.
- That's negging.
That's what she said!
I didn't even know hat that meant!
You okay?
I think...
That's enough.
Don't finish it.
Oh, thank you.
I love the dress.
I wanted to say it earlier
but I was too shy.
I'm not good with...
So tomorrow you're gonna be cogent,
no sunglasses.
As long as the alcohol is the clear kind,
like white wine, or champagne or vodka
it's fine.
I think it's because
I have Polish ancestry
and if you drink the thing
from you ancestors,
that your ancestors made
with their own feet...
then you're...
- fine.
- Yeah?
Once you see me tomorrow,
I will be bright and sunny.
- Just start drinking and all good.
- Totally. It's a wedding
and like, I think that, for the most part,
you can self-medicate
where you like,
you have like a glass of wine and...
White wine, I'm noticing.
Lots of white wine.
My skill that I learned -
day drinking.
Okay? Then night drinking.
- Brunch drinking.
- Yeah.
I'm trying to, whatever, you know.
Connect, yeah, that's the word.
Or no, I'm trying to be as sincere as you.
Not the exact same thing
but when I was 16,
I went on antidepressants
because I, in my opinion,
well you know what?
I would get home from school
every day and go to sleep.
And my parents were like,
"Oh, my God, you're depressed."
But really I was just insanely
addicted to EverQuest
which was an online video game.
Ask me about it later,
I will talk to you about it for days.
Imagine a world thousands
of player characters
all existing in a role playing game...
You were just depressed
because you were a huge nerd.
No, I was obsessed because I was playing
it nonstop with my brother all the time
and my life fell apart, and...
I'm trying to humble
myself before you here.
So got put on antidepressants by my Mum,
who is a doctor.
Do you still take them now?
No.
I'm just gonna go to the wash room.
Anne?
Are you still in there? It's Matt.
You were just talking with me.
We were falling in love. Do you remember?
I'm coming in.
Anne?
You okay?
- Hi.
- You awake?
Stop kicking me.
You want some water?
Thank you.
I think I ate something weird.
Yeah, definitely.
Yeah, you know what? A lot of the guests
I think ate the same thing
because it's just a river of vomit
out there.
Don't say the word vomit.
You know what? Nobody knows
that you were sick except for me
and anybody within 60 feet of the door
who could hear everything.
Nah!
Nobody heard anything.
I'm just teasing you.
Thank you.
It's like you're a prisoner and I'm a nun.
Are there still more people there?
No, this is...
You've been here for like, 30 minutes.
The place is like empty.
There's stragglers.
You're doing great.
Okay, come on. Let's go.
Okay, so I'm remembering...
white wine, mezcal... vodka.
- No problem.
Was it that my genes...
Yeah...
Hold them, hold them.
You good?
Oh! Sorry.
Bad Anne.
It is Bad Anne, and she's back.
Bad Anne is back.
Sorry, man.
Nine steps.
You're flying. Yeah, okay, yeah.
No, no, no, no.
- Excuse me.
- You're excused. We're here.
Come on.
Okay.
You're going up. I got you.
Ready? I'm gonna be right back.
I'm not abandoning you.
Okay?
Okay.
Yes.
One, two... oh, please. Thank God.
Okay. Here's the plan.
You are in the bed. Okay?
I don't like the person
who made the movie Jaws
but the person that wrote the book,
I like her.
It's about a great white shark
that goes on a rampage
because it has an uncontrollable urge
for human...
for human flesh.
There's this girl...
She's... No, she's not in Jaws,
she's in Soul Surfer
and she's like this girl,
she was surfing
and the shark attacked her and...
In real life or in the movie?
I think maybe in real life?
Or maybe in the movie.
But it might be a documentary.
But the shark apparently attacked her
and took off this whole thing go bye-bye.
And she was walking around like,
If one shark bites your arm off,
then more come because...
Yeah, and then it comes
into a feeding frenzy. It's literally...
So you admit that sharks want human flesh.
I admit... No, I admit nothing!
You admit that
like the blockbuster movie Jaws...
I admit!
- What are you doing, Oliver?
- I'm trying to open this gate.
What are you doing?
I'm trying to open this gate,
what does it look like I'm doing?
Why?
Because my dad is literally over there.
Hi, Dad, can I have a little bit longer?
- Couple minutes.
- Yeah!
- Hi.
- Hey.
- How's it going?
- Good.
Listen...
about what happened at the wading pool...
I was a little... curt.
Yeah, no problem.
Sorry that I got him soaking wet.
It's okay.
Listen, he thinks the world
of you and I...
I know how much you care for him,
so if you're still willing to...
to watch him sometimes,
he would love that.
- Yeah.
- Maybe one night next week?
Like Tuesday? Wednesday? Yeah?
Good.
I should get him.
Ollie, let's go.
Bye, Oliver.
- Let's go. Say bye.
- Bye.
Hi, so your tag is still on your dress.
Do you want me to just
take it off for you? Yeah?
Sure.
- I just bought it.
- It's a nice dress.
- Thank you.
- There you go.
- Hi.
Hi, oh, my gosh, how are you?
- Oh, hello.
- I'm Matt.
- This is Matt. This is Matt.
- Nice to meet you.
Lizzie. Barb.
Hello. Hi.
He's just having a lollipop,
it's a treat.
- Hello.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
- That's for dinner.
Hi. I would get up but I'm just...
I'll just...
Don't even move.
- You're Anne's sister?
- Yes.
- What's your name?
- Lizzie.
- Lizzie. Okay. And who's this guy?
- Sorry, we have so many toys in the way.
No, no, I don't mind.
- These are very elegant creatures.
- Yeah.
The dogs hate you.
Usually they're all over people.
They're just like completely
keeping their distance.
Oh you know what?
I don't mind. Nice to meet you.
Handshake. Very professional.
This is Ben?
Yeah, Nathan and Ben
are getting to know each other.
It's your first time meeting Ben, yeah.
Oh, this is a good one.
Exposed chassis. Exposed motor.
Beautiful.
Are we really, really early?
- Is that what's going on?
- No, no, not at all.
We're just playing a bit.
We're just playing.
We've been playing all day.
I didn't tell them you were coming.
Okay. Sorry.
Anne told me that we were
having dinner with her family
and I thought that you guys knew
that I was coming over.
I would never have said,
"Did we get here early?"
- Yeah, no, I understand that.
- Honestly, you're totally welcome.
- Anne, why didn't you just tell them?
- I just wanted to me her uncomfortable.
Isn't that face...
Isn't just seeing that face
worth every penny?
Every penny.
Do I need to teach everyone
how to have a conversation?
You came with such energy
and you really put us
in such a high tension situation, Anne.
This is your first grandson?
Or first grandchild?
- Always the best.
- Yeah.
- Your name is Matt.
- You got it, yeah. Bingo. You killed it.
Put 'er there.
You're so smart.
Your name is Nathan.
Uncle Matt. Uncle Matt.
Uncle Matt.
- You tow have a lot in common.
- I'm sorry, what is it that you do?
- I work at the Science Centre.
- Amazing!
- As a...
- I love that place.
Okay, have you seen the people
walking around in white lab coats?
That kind of give tours? That's what I do.
You know what?
He would be perfect on the second floor.
There's a place called Kids Park
where it's all...
You have to be under eight just to get in.
In fact, they don't let people in unless
they're accompanied my a kid under eight.
- So you guys have a pass.
- It's for the pervs.
That's not an official slogan.
This is when you ask our guest
personal questions about himself.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Where are you from?
What's your favourite colour?
No, no, no, no. You don't have to...
You don't have to ask me anything.
You know what...?
No, I'll ask you something.
Let's see. Where are you from?
- Toronto. Not far from here.
- How did you two meet?
We met at Sarah and Jeff's wedding
about a month ago.
- Oh, okay.
- You're so weird!
She had lost her purse
and I was the only person...
We were staying in the same hotel,
everybody was staying in the same hotel,
and so I helped her get back to the hotel.
I shouldn't say,
"helped her get back to the hotel."
Basically she needed help,
what am I saying?
She needed help and I helped her
and we had been talking before that...
- And everything was great.
- Are you okay Matt?
Yeah. You know what? It's...
What's the word for it?
Thrown into a new situation.
You're doing great. You're doing great.
It's just funny seeing you thrive
in this situation.
You guys are making Nathan laugh too,
look.
- He's laughing too.
- So anyway, moving on.
Actually, Ben has a trick. Ben. Ben!
Ben's sleeping. Ben's having a nap.
I think that he's all worn out.
He's worn out.
Go on his lap. Go on
his lap. Go on his lap.
Ben, Ben, Ben. Come on his lap.
Get on his lap.
- Hey Ben.
- Ben. Now do the trick.
Paws. Paws, paws, paws.
I think he'll do it because
he's really worn out today.
I think he's new...
He needs to really know someone.
Don't force him.
Yeah, you know what?
Maybe after dinner I'll get the...
But, look, he likes you.
That's very...
I mean it must be a good sign about you.
What a handsome pair.
Can you tell me a bit more what happened?
Okay so I'm not quite sure
why you can't tell me,
but I'll tell you what Suzanne said.
She said that you threw a cup at her
and then you tried
to put it down her shirt.
And then on top of it,
it was in front of children.
And she got pretty upset.
- I don't think...
- And you got pretty upset.
The kids seemed to notice it.
So do think that was okay behaviour?
I was just showing her
that I'd done what she asked.
I was showing her
that I dumped out the tea.
Like I know if I had just gone
and put it in the garbage
she'd just tell me to put it
in the recycling.
So I was just trying to get her to like...
stop paying attention to me.
You know, pay attention to her own work.
I was just showing her
that I did what she asked.
So I think Suzanne has been a long time.
I think she takes the job
really seriously,
so maybe when she's telling you
that you're not following the rules
she's trying to help.
So maybe we need to step back,
look at what's working well,
and then come up with a solution,
communications
for when things aren't working well.
So why don't we say every Friday
we'll get together for maybe half an hour.
You'll both come to the meeting
with things that are working
and then come up with something
that's not working
and then I need to see
that you're coming up with solutions.
I just feel like if we...
have weekly meetings that means
that she's gonna be observing me
and I don't want her to be observing me.
So I am totally not doing that.
Would you prefer that I not let you know
if you've broken a rule
and you don't realise it?
And then somebody walks
in and sees you doing it.
Would you prefer that?
Because if that's what you want,
that's fine.
Yeah, tell me what you want from me.
Because...
it changes all the time.
I just feel...
like she's always picking on me.
Like, it wouldn't matter what I was doing,
she'd find something to correct me on
and that makes me feel like...
like I don't have freedom in the room
to learn myself.
Like she's always kind of
breathing down my neck.
I'm just trying to help.
I really, truthfully am trying to help.
I would think you'd know that.
- Hi.
- Can you go get a coffee?
Not right now.
I'm, this is very important business.
Have you seen this?
- My name's Anne.
- Hello, Anne.
Hello Anne.
You guys wouldn't care if Sarah
came and got a coffee with me right?
- I would.
- Yes, exactly!
That's so nice.
There's like four teachers in the room.
- No one will notice if you come get...
- I know but there's like 90 kids.
It's not worth being caught.
It's not worth...
I have to be here. It's my job.
Well, I'm not getting you anything.
What's going on?
Who is it?
Hey! Yeah!
Okay.
What are you doing this for?
Remember, this is what I told you
we did for Sarah's bachelorette party.
Okay, yeah. You look like Bugs Bunny.
Like a lot.
Then what?
What happens?
She pulls the parachute and what?
I obviously didn't react
the way you wanted me to.
I think the jump looks really great.
And it would be great if I got to see
the landing on the ground.
That's it.
You just have to do it,
or you don't understand.
I have to jump?
I don't know if I'm looking
for that kind of thrill in my life.
I didn't even enjoy watching the video.
For me a thrill is like, okay,
I'm kind of casually dating a girl and she
takes me to her parent's house, unannounced
and says, "Hey this is my boyfriend,
we're getting married."
That's enough, that is my version
of jumping out of a plane.
What did they think about that?
Did you follow up with them?
Did your mum and sister say anything like,
"Who was that guy?
- "Why was he at...?"
- Yeah, no, they really liked you.
They did?
Did you tell them
that we're only casually dating
and that it's not as serious
as you said it was in front of them?
No, I didn't say that to them.
You could have told me that
they didn't know I was coming over.
Or you could have told me
that you gonna make these...
No, it was my joke.
I was the one doing the joke.
Why would I have told you?
Why would I have let you into the joke?
What's...? I'm sorry, what's the joke?
The joke is we're not seriously dating
and you're gonna tell them we are?
"Hey, guys, what if we got married?
"Everybody meet this guy.
"Meet my future husband.
"Oh, PS, I didn't tell you he was coming.
PS, He doesn't even know.
"PPS, This is gonna be the most
awkward five minutes of our lives."
I thought that you would think
it was funny.
I'm not mad. I thought that...
Let's finish the stew.
Next time together we'll play a really,
really good joke on them.
And you can be the joke leader,
you can have the joke idea.
I'll just help you execute the joke.
Well let's hold off a minute
before we start worrying about a next time
we go see your parents.
- Hi, how are you today?
- Good, thank you.
- Do you need help finding something?
- No, thank you.
That jacket looks great on you, by the way.
Just let me know if you need help, okay?
- Did you need a hand?
- No, it's okay.
Did you want us to start
you a changing room?
- No, that's okay.
- Are you sure?
Oh, here.
That jacket is really hard to zip up.
It's okay, I've got it. Thank you.
- Here, I can find a hanger.
- Can you stop following me? Thank you.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to do that.
Mum, it can't go through the vent!
- Look, Mum!
- You're playing stupid games.
I'm not gonna get caught
up in your stupid games.
Mum! Mum, I'm at home.
This is what people do at home.
They do stupid things.
It's a totally normal thing to do.
Do you really...?
Mum, it's won't catch on fire.
Okay, this is destructive.
Just cut it out.
Look, there's a vent there.
You can't even put it inside.
Look, it's an Anne-proof fireplace.
Nothing bad is gonna happen.
Nothing bad is gonna happen to Anne.
She can...
This is destructive, stop it!
- It's not destructive!
- It's totally destructive!
- It's fake fire!
- Stop it!
It's not gonna catch on fire!
It's not a game.
You're making my behaviour seem...
Are you serious? Look, look!
Stop, stop this!
Okay, can you go sit down?
Why are you being serious about this?
I'm obviously joking around, Mum.
It's a fake fire.
If I stick this in here...
Can we not? Can we not?
You know that it won't catch on fire.
I don't feel good in this house,
I don't feel good around you!
I don't feel good because you don't
understand when I'm making a joke
and you're making this whole deal!
I need to be able to make a joke
without you going and thinking
I'm gonna set the house on fire
- because the whole joke...
- Okay, okay!
I know,
you've explained the joke 400 times.
- You're upset. Just...
- Mum. It's not you, Mum. You're fine.
It's just being in this house.
Like I just don't...
Can we sit?
Can we sit down and just talk?
I'm gonna go home
and I'm just gonna not...
Okay, what if you just stayed tonight?
Mum! No, good night, mum.
No. Don't go, no. Just...
And it's liquidy.
What would a shark eat
out of these three things?
Well, that one is poisonous.
That one is too snappy.
And that one is too...
What's stepping in on your phone?
Matt's being an idiot.
Why? What's been...?
I think he's trying to do some kind of
distancing thing or something like that.
That sucks.
I just don't understand why
he's doing it now, you know?
Yeah.
Things were so normal and friendly.
We can't really talk about this right now.
- It's not the right moment.
- But I mean, if he was answering me,
then I wouldn't feel like I had
to think about it all the time.
Who wants a free hand wash?
Me!
Honestly, the whole time
the relationship's been so romantic
and like so open and so nice
that I never thought
that he was gonna start
pulling any of that kind of stuff,
you know what I mean?
Oh, you got bubbles in your hair.
Treat me like I'm some kind
of weird criminal or something
and he's just gonna start ignoring
all my text messages.
But this isn't the right time to be
even looking at your text messages.
It's distracting because you're not...
you can't be thinking about it
while you're here.
It's not really fair to me. Or anybody.
Whose bowl is this?
You're allowed to tell me
one more thing about sharks
and then you have to go to bed.
Stingray! It's a stingray.
- Stingrays are very beautiful.
- It's a stingray.
Sting, sting, sting, stab.
The stingray buries itself in the sand.
Pop quiz. Pop quiz.
This quiz a hundred percent of your grade.
If you fail you're gonna get
an F minus on your report card.
If I guess the shark right
you have to go to bed.
- Okay.
- A hammerhead shark?
Wrong answer.
- Bull shark?
- Wrong answer.
- You have three more guesses.
- Open mouth shark.
Two.
- You have two and then...
- Great white shark.
One more.
- Whale shark.
- You win.
No!
Baby machine gun. Baby machine gun.
I gave birth to a stingray.
You tried to hold the baby in.
There's more babies I think.
Giving birth to twelve sharks
is very tiring.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- How did it go?
- Good. Thanks.
Did he subject you to the great whites
or the hammerheads tonight?
I don't even remember.
May I?
- Can I top you up?
- Yeah, sure.
Welcome back.
Thanks again for coming out.
Yeah, no problem.
I kept threatening him all week
tell him that if he didn't behave
I was gonna call you and cancel.
Hopefully this is the first
of many of your returns.
Next week I might have another meeting,
Wednesday or Thursday, if you're around.
Okay, thanks.
- What's wrong?
- No, I'm just gonna head home.
You're welcome to stay.
Finish your wine.
That's okay, I had like,
the whole bottle before you got here.
Can I pay you?
You're not working for free.
- Thank you.
I'll call you about next week?
- Yes. Bye.
- Bye.
Did you tell me you were coming over?
What's going on?
You're a weird little girl, you know that?
What are you doing here?
Sorry. Sorry, sorry, sorry.
Come on.
Hello?
I mean, I made these plans a long time ago
maybe if you'd given me more notice
I could have shifted things around.
But, I'm sorry.
Excuse me?
- What's up?
- I have to go to work.
Dammit.
You said you had the day off.
Someone called and asked me
to take their shift.
Can you drive me?
- How far is it?
- Never mind, it's fine.
I'm trying to tease you.
I'm saying yes, I'm driving you. Come on.
You ready for your first day of daycare?
The other kids I think
are gonna be really nice.
Trust me, I talked to some
of the other parents,
they said that they specialise
in kids like you.
You don't like going to daycare?
- You're really fast.
- Well you said you were late.
Thank you for driving me.
Don't worry about it.
Nyree, I'm here.
- Hey, hey good. Thank you.
- Yeah.
Yeah, but you supposed to be here
half an hour ago.
I mean you just called me
and I came all the way across town.
I came as fast as I could.
Okay, you know what thank you.
Why don't you go home,
I'll take over your class.
- Great.
You signed in though right?
No, I'll sign in when I go
past the office later, it's fine.
Actually, it's not fine.
Just go sign in while I'm still here.
Sign in really,
really quick and just come right back.
R-E-D. Red. R-E-D.
- Is this not the sign-out?
- No. Remember we changed it?
I went over that in the staff meeting
the other day.
Then it's important that
you read the message book
so you know what kids are away
and who's...
- What's that say?
- That's Autumn and Rain's nanny.
Hi, you shoe.
Excuse me.
Isaiah, guys, stay in the classroom.
Okay, alright. I'm signed in.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Guys, be good.
I will see you later, okay?
Okay. Bye.
- Bye.
Can you guys please put these away?
If you want you can go to your cubbies,
you can get your show-and-tell
that you were going to bring today.
- Yes!
Oliver.
You guys each get a basket,
don't let anyone see your show and tell.
So we went to the zoo
and one of my favourite
animals there was a tiger
because they're amazing animals
and one of my favourite animals
that you can actually have as a pet
is a cat and a tiger is a species of cat.
That's awesome.
What's inside mystical box number one?
Is that a cat collar?
Yeah. This was the collar
for my cat Spiky.
So basically what happened was...
we had a thermometer
in the backyard of my house
and it broke when nobody was home
and my little cat Spiky
licked up all the mercury.
So when we came home we
couldn't get him to stop moving.
He was just running back and forth
and eventually he escaped out the window
until you couldn't hear the bell any more.
So my dad had to go up
onto the roof and get him down.
Was the cat okay?
No, he died.
Yeah, she said she had a cat.
Had.
- Was his mind messed up?
- Yeah.
Wouldn't you take him to a vet?
We couldn't catch him.
Couldn't you lure him in with food?
No, couldn't lure him in with food,
Oliver, because he went crazy.
He ate a poison that made
him go completely crazy.
Maybe he was thirsty.
That was funny.
Well it couldn't have been your fault
because you weren't there.
You are now queen of the world.
And now you're queen of mercury.
Anne? Can you get that for me please?
I can't get it for you right now.
Come here. Come here.
I cannot with both your arms.
Peacemaker.
Anne.
I'm like a butterfly. I emerged.
Arms then I think it's in the stomach.
Anne, come see my trick.
Anne.
Anne?
Hey, what's going on?
It's okay.
I think she has a stomach ache.
Do you want to get some fresh air?
Anne?
Can you hear me?
Are you okay?
You're okay. It's okay.
We'll just go home, okay?
We'll just go home.
Where are we going?
I just thought we would stop
by your mum's house for a second,
since we're in the neighbourhood.
What did you say to her?
I talked to her just briefly
and she was totally cool about it.
She wasn't...
- Fuck this.
- Sorry.
- She's not gonna...
- I don't want to go to her house.
I know you don't want to see her
but I think I need a little bit of help.
I want to get out of the car.
- I want to get out of the car.
- I'll pull over in a second if you want.
Anne, what the fuck are you doing?
What the fuck? Close the door.
Jesus.
Anne.
Good morning.
Good morning, Nathan.
Wait, that's your foot.
Can I see your car?
This is the green car.
The green car?
Do you want to make the car drive?
That's my car but I think you should go.
I got a red car.
Red car?
It's all red there.
Red is my favourite colour.
- Really?
- I just have the green one... them.
Do you know what sound a police car makes?
It's got good wheels.
Nice. You're doing it.
There you go.
I clouded you out.
- There you go.
- Good job.
She's getting it. She's got it.
- We get it, you vape.
- You vape.
- Cheers guys.
- Cheers.
Are you nervous?
You're excited though yeah? Right on.
And what are we gonna do?
- Classic arch.
- That was beautiful.
- Perfect.
Sharing is caring.
You should always do a gainer.
Always do a gainer.
- Gainer and track.
- Absolutely, all the time.
Feeling it?
She's getting into it.
Little head rush?
Little bit. Little head rush
before you feel the real rush?
- You guys do this before and after?
- I just do it all day.
Arch. Reach and pull.
Slap it and tap it.
You gotta put the hang loose up.
Boom boom, I'm not even looking at you.
We'll have him behind the pilot.
I'll give you a hand.